<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scroll View</string>
    <string name="textview"><b>Book title — “The Power of Your Subconscious Mind” by Dr. Joseph Murphy </b>
An age-old book that re-defined the way self-help books are written and understood.
Joseph Murphy was a doctor of psychology who wrote extensively about the power of the subconscious mind.
In this book, Murphy contemplates a theory that the subconscious mind has a powerful effect on everything we do and experience. He says that, if we as an individual can believe in something and visualize it clearly, we can remove all the mental blocks to achieve the desired results.
He concludes that we can bring a thought to reality by wholly and truly believing in it. And, he illustrates various activities to explore the power of your Subconscious mind.
“10 bullets-100 words” book summary and my takeaways from this book:
Picture an Iceberg — The part above the surface is Conscious Mind — Objective, Decisive, Woken up, Rationale.
The part below the surface is Unconscious Mind —Subjective, Deep self, Sleeping.
The subconscious mind is always at work, harness its power.
Realize the power of your positive thinking and accomplish your dreams.
You can CHOOSE to be happy and lose the negative thoughts.
Believe in something to make it your reality.
Your subconscious mind believes what you consciously believe.
What goes in your mind defines your world.
Sleep is when your subconscious mind works the best.
Use visualization to create a placebo effect.
My takeaways
My only takeaway from this book is to believe in the Subconscious mind.
Initially, it’s hard to grasp and swallow the thought. As human beings, we have been groomed to believe in what we see and learn through formal means. Visualizing the “sub-conscious” mind is a “vast” concept for our minds to fathom. Still, if you allow your mind to at least listen to this concept and then accept it with an open heart, your subconscious mind will get activated. Once, that happens, you will not only start believing in it, but you will also see the value and the benefits.
Despite such a “vastness” of this thought, once I close my eyes to explore this concept, I find it very comfortable and relaxing to believe in the power of my subconscious mind.
I practice daily meditation and books like this, only reaffirm the power of a closed eye and an open subconscious mind.
100 words are as easy as it’s challenging to summarize an excellent book. There is so much which remains unsaid. Still, I realize, confining myself to 100 words will bring out more creativity and effort.
The perspective of this format is to allow the book to pull the reader towards itself. When you pick the book and read it in its entirety, that’s when you honor the author’s efforts and get an opportunity to learn a lot of new things.
I hope this structure entices you to pick up this book, learn a new thing or two, and expand your outlook.
Thanks for reading.

    </string>
</resources>